- You might ask yourself why design patterns are important. I first learned patterns as a means of
- communicating a problem to another developer. You may very well already know how to solve a particular
- problem, and it might follow the structure of a pattern, but it's better to have a common vocabulary that you
- can explain to someone what that problem is. Patterns are an abstract topic.
- It isn't something that you look at the concept and then have it memorized and know how to apply it from there.
- Some patterns are more easily applied to particular problems than another, so I suggest revisiting pattern
- material as you develop more and more programming experience. Whether it be this course or a book or
- something else, it is amazing how your perception of a pattern will change after gaining more experience with it.
- You might come away with a different understanding of it after applying it through different coding practices.
- A lot of people have used a singleton and think they have used design patterns, but there's much more than
- just a singleton out there.